<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 01:48:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Streamlit app from scratch and deploying it for free using Heroku</title>
      <link>/posts/streamlit-openscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 01:48:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/streamlit-openscale/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Streamlit is an easy to use python framework to build interactive apps. As opposed to fully featured frameworks like Django and Flask, Streamlit is very opinionated as it has fewer features, but the advantage is you can deploy Streamlit app in under 5 minutes with no knowledge of APIs or routes. Streamlit has recently gotten very popular, especially among data scientists as a quick way to present their findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 22:27:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
I am Alex Joseph, a Mechanical Engineer turned Data Scientist dabbling in Data Architecture. This page is an attempt to write about things that interest me.
Ever since my graduation in 2011, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a startup called VIMANA. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m a Principal Data Architect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodybuilder - A python port of the nodeJS BodyBuilder Package</title>
      <link>/posts/bodybuilder_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 20:39:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bodybuilder_intro/</guid>
      <description>At VIMANA, we have an Elasticsearch backend for storing most of our Big Data. While Elasticsearch is an amazing search engine which can do a variety of queries/aggregations, the Elasticsearch Query DSL is difficult to construct, especialy for newcomers. I have spent countless hours trying to get the brackets right and the searching for the specific terms. While the new SQL options allows the user to query using SQL, that still doesn&amp;rsquo;t have all the capabilities supported by the full DSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing compareDF</title>
      <link>/posts/comparedf-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 01:25:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/comparedf-intro/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This is a repost of an article that was first published in 2016, updated to for latest version
Introduction Every so often while doing data analysis, I have come across a situation where I have two datasets, which have the same structure but with small differences in the actual data between the two. For example:
 Variation of a dataset across different time periods for the same grouping Variation of values for different algorithms, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTConnect Webinar Example</title>
      <link>/posts/mtconnect-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 22:10:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mtconnect-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For a real life working example, we have this dataset graciously provided to us by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (http://www.nist.gov/) for one of their test bed parts. We will be trying to solve the first example from the introduction, which was a real problem faced by the NIST researchers. As we walk through each step of the exploratory process, you will understand how you can use similar techniques to solve similar issues that you might have with your Machine Tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
